Copyright (c) 2006 Symantec Corporation and/or its subsidiaries.  
All rights reserved.  Use of this product is subject to license terms.
Federal Acquisitions: Commercial Software - Government Users Subject
to Standard License Terms and Conditions.

Symantec, the Symantec Logo, Brightmail, the Brightmail Logo, BLOC, BrightSig,
The Anti-Spam Leader, Probe Network, and Norton AntiVirus are trademarks or
registered trademarks of Symantec Corporation in the United States and certain
other countries.  Additional company and product names may be trademarks or
registered trademarks of the individual companies and are respectfully
acknowledged.

Except where otherwise noted, this product is protected by U.S. and
International Copyright and distributed under license restricting copying,
distributing, and decompiling.

Use of the Symantec AntiVirus and all its components, including
any warranty provisions, is subject to the terms of your agreement with 
Symantec.  In the absence of any warranty provisions, the following will 
apply:

SYMANTEC ANTIVIRUS AND ALL ITS COMPONENTS, INCLUDING ALL SOFTWARE,
SERVICES, AND DOCUMENTATION, IS BEING PROVIDED "AS IS". SYMANTEC ON BEHALF
OF ITSELF AND ITS LICENSORS MAKES NO REPRESENTATION OR WARRANTY OF ANY KIND
WHETHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED (EITHER IN FACT OR BY OPERATION OF LAW) WITH
RESPECT TO SYMANTEC ANTIVIRUS. SYMANTEC EXPRESSLY DISCLAIMS ALL IMPLIED
WARRANTIES, INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION, THOSE OF NONINFRINGEMENT,
MERCHANTABILITY, OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  SYMANTEC DOES NOT
WARRANT THAT SYMANTEC ANTIVIRUS WILL BE ERROR-FREE, SECURE, OR
UNINTERRUPTED.

SYMANTEC WILL HAVE NO OBLIGATION TO PROVIDE YOU WITH ANY SUPPORT OR 
MAINTENANCE OF ANY KIND FOR SYMANTEC ANTIVIRUS UNLESS OTHERWISE AGREED TO.

IN NO EVENT WILL EITHER PARTY BE LIABLE FOR ANY LOSS OF PROFITS, LOSS OF
BUSINESS, LOSS OF USE OR DATA, INTERRUPTION OF BUSINESS, OR FOR INDIRECT,
SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OF ANY KIND, WHETHER IN TORT,
CONTRACT, OR ANY OTHER LEGAL THEORY, EVEN IF SUCH PARTY HAS BEEN ADVISED 
OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES (AND NOTWITHSTANDING ANY FAILURE OF 
ESSENTIAL PURPOSE OF ANY LIMITED REMEDY), OR FOR ANY CLAIM AGAINST THE OTHER
PARTY BY ANY THIRD PARTY.  THE REMEDIES PROVIDED HEREIN ARE YOUR SOLE AND 
EXCLUSIVE REMEDIES. 

=============================================================================
Symantec AntiVirus 10.1

THIRD-PARTY NOTICES.
=============================================================================

Symantec AntiVirus contains the 
SUN JRE version 1.4.2 created and maintained by Sun Microsystems, Inc. 
(http://java.sun.com ). The JRE is licensed under the following agreement:


Sun Microsystems, Inc. Binary Code License Agreement

for the JAVATM 2 RUNTIME ENVIRONMENT (J2RE), STANDARD
EDITION, VERSION 1.4.2_X

SUN MICROSYSTEMS, INC. ("SUN") IS WILLING TO LICENSE THE
SOFTWARE IDENTIFIED BELOW TO YOU ONLY UPON THE CONDITION
THAT YOU ACCEPT ALL OF THE TERMS CONTAINED IN THIS BINARY
CODE LICENSE AGREEMENT AND SUPPLEMENTAL LICENSE TERMS
(COLLECTIVELY "AGREEMENT").  PLEASE READ THE AGREEMENT
CAREFULLY.  BY DOWNLOADING OR INSTALLING THIS SOFTWARE, YOU
ACCEPT THE TERMS OF THE AGREEMENT. INDICATE ACCEPTANCE BY
SELECTING THE "ACCEPT" BUTTON AT THE BOTTOM OF THE
AGREEMENT. IF YOU ARE NOT WILLING TO BE BOUND BY ALL THE
TERMS, SELECT THE "DECLINE" BUTTON AT THE BOTTOM OF THE
AGREEMENT AND THE DOWNLOAD OR INSTALL PROCESS WILL NOT
CONTINUE.

1.DEFINITIONS. "Software" means the identified above in
binary form, any other machine readable materials
(including, but not limited to, libraries, source files,
header files, and data files), any updates or error
corrections provided by Sun, and any user manuals,
programming guides and other documentation provided to you
by Sun under this Agreement. "Programs" mean Java applets
and applications intended to run on the Java 2 Platform,
Standard Edition (J2SETM platform) platform on Java-enabled
general purpose desktop computers and servers.

2.LICENSE TO USE. Subject to the terms and conditions of
this Agreement, including, but not limited to the Java
Technology Restrictions of the Supplemental License Terms,
Sun grants you a non-exclusive, non-transferable, limited
license without license fees to reproduce and use
internally Software complete and unmodified for the sole
purpose of running Programs. Additional licenses for
developers and/or publishers are granted in the
Supplemental License Terms.

3.RESTRICTIONS. Software is confidential and copyrighted.
Title to Software and all associated intellectual property
rights is retained by Sun and/or its licensors. Unless
enforcement is prohibited by applicable law, you may not
modify, decompile, or reverse engineer Software.  You
acknowledge that Licensed Software is not designed or
intended for use in the design, construction, operation or
maintenance of any nuclear facility. Sun Microsystems, Inc.
disclaims any express or implied warranty of fitness for
such uses. No right, title or interest in or to any
trademark, service mark, logo or trade name of Sun or its
licensors is granted under this Agreement. Additional
restrictions for developers and/or publishers licenses are
set forth in the Supplemental License Terms.

4.LIMITED WARRANTY.  Sun warrants to you that for a period of
ninety (90) days from the date of purchase, as evidenced by
a copy of the receipt, the media on which Software is
furnished (if any) will be free of defects in materials and
workmanship under normal use.  Except for the foregoing,
Software is provided "AS IS".  Your exclusive remedy and
Sun's entire liability under this limited warranty will be
at Sun's option to replace Software media or refund the fee
paid for Software. Any implied warranties on the Software
are limited to 90 days. Some states do not allow
limitations on duration of an implied warranty, so the
above may not apply to you. This limited warranty gives you
specific legal rights. You may have others, which vary from
state to state.

5.DISCLAIMER OF WARRANTY.  UNLESS SPECIFIED IN THIS
AGREEMENT, ALL EXPRESS OR IMPLIED CONDITIONS,
REPRESENTATIONS AND WARRANTIES, INCLUDING ANY IMPLIED
WARRANTY OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR
PURPOSE OR NON-INFRINGEMENT ARE DISCLAIMED, EXCEPT TO THE
EXTENT THAT THESE DISCLAIMERS ARE HELD TO BE LEGALLY
INVALID.

6.LIMITATION OF LIABILITY.  TO THE EXTENT NOT PROHIBITED BY
LAW, IN NO EVENT WILL SUN OR ITS LICENSORS BE LIABLE FOR
ANY LOST REVENUE, PROFIT OR DATA, OR FOR SPECIAL, INDIRECT,
CONSEQUENTIAL, INCIDENTAL OR PUNITIVE DAMAGES, HOWEVER
CAUSED REGARDLESS OF THE THEORY OF LIABILITY, ARISING OUT
OF OR RELATED TO THE USE OF OR INABILITY TO USE SOFTWARE,
EVEN IF SUN HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH
DAMAGES.  In no event will Sun's liability to you, whether in
contract, tort (including negligence), or otherwise, exceed
the amount paid by you for Software under this Agreement.
The foregoing limitations will apply even if the above
stated warranty fails of its essential purpose. Some states
do not allow the exclusion of incidental or consequential
damages, so some of the terms above may not be applicable
to you.

7.SOFTWARE UPDATES FROM SUN. You acknowledge that at your
request or consent optional features of the Software may
download, install, and execute applets, applications,
software extensions, and updated versions of the Software
from Sun ("Software Updates"), which may require you to
accept updated terms and conditions for installation. If
additional terms and conditions are not presented on
installation, the Software Updates will be considered part
of the Software and subject to the terms and conditions of
the Agreement.

8.SOFTWARE FROM SOURCES OTHER THAN SUN. You acknowledge
that, by your use of optional features of the Software
and/or by requesting services that require use of the
optional features of the Software, the Software may
automatically download, install, and execute software
applications from sources other than Sun ("Other
Software"). Sun makes no representations of a relationship
of any kind to licensors of Other Software. TO THE EXTENT
NOT PROHIBITED BY LAW, IN NO EVENT WILL SUN OR ITS
LICENSORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY LOST REVENUE, PROFIT OR DATA,
OR FOR SPECIAL, INDIRECT, CONSEQUENTIAL, INCIDENTAL OR
PUNITIVE DAMAGES, HOWEVER CAUSED REGARDLESS OF THE THEORY
OF LIABILITY, ARISING OUT OF OR RELATED TO THE USE OF OR
INABILITY TO USE OTHER SOFTWARE, EVEN IF SUN HAS BEEN
ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES. Some states do
not allow the exclusion of incidental or consequential
damages, so some of the terms above may not be applicable
to you.

9.TERMINATION.  This Agreement is effective until terminated.
You may terminate this Agreement at any time by destroying
all copies of Software.  This Agreement will terminate
immediately without notice from Sun if you fail to comply
with any provision of this Agreement.  Either party may
terminate this Agreement immediately should any Software
become, or in either party's opinion be likely to become,
the subject of a claim of infringement of any intellectual
property right. Upon Termination, you must destroy all
copies of Software.

10.EXPORT REGULATIONS. All Software and technical data
delivered under this Agreement are subject to US export
control laws and may be subject to export or import
regulations in other countries.  You agree to comply strictly
with all such laws and regulations and acknowledge that you
have the responsibility to obtain such licenses to export,
re-export, or import as may be required after delivery to
you.

11.TRADEMARKS AND LOGOS. You acknowledge and agree as
between you and Sun that Sun owns the SUN, SOLARIS, JAVA,
JINI, FORTE, and iPLANET trademarks and all SUN, SOLARIS,
JAVA, JINI, FORTE, and iPLANET-related trademarks, service
marks, logos and other brand designations ("Sun Marks"),
and you agree to comply with the Sun Trademark and Logo
Usage Requirements currently located at
http://www.sun.com/policies/trademarks. Any use you make of
the Sun Marks inures to Sun's benefit.

12.U.S. GOVERNMENT RESTRICTED RIGHTS.  If Software is being
acquired by or on behalf of the U.S. Government or by a
U.S. Government prime contractor or subcontractor (at any
tier), then the Government's rights in Software and
accompanying documentation will be only as set forth in
this Agreement; this is in accordance with 48 CFR 227.7201
through 227.7202-4 (for Department of Defense (DOD)
acquisitions) and with 48 CFR 2.101 and 12.212 (for non-DOD
acquisitions).

13.GOVERNING LAW.  Any action related to this Agreement will
be governed by California law and controlling U.S. federal
law.  No choice of law rules of any jurisdiction will apply.

14.SEVERABILITY. If any provision of this Agreement is held
to be unenforceable, this Agreement will remain in effect
with the provision omitted, unless omission would frustrate
the intent of the parties, in which case this Agreement
will immediately terminate.

15.INTEGRATION.  This Agreement is the entire agreement
between you and Sun relating to its subject matter.  It
supersedes all prior or contemporaneous oral or written
communications, proposals, representations and warranties
and prevails over any conflicting or additional terms of
any quote, order, acknowledgment, or other communication
between the parties relating to its subject matter during
the term of this Agreement.  No modification of this
Agreement will be binding, unless in writing and signed by
an authorized representative of each party.

SUPPLEMENTAL LICENSE TERMS
These Supplemental License Terms add to or modify the terms
of the Binary Code License Agreement. Capitalized terms not
defined in these Supplemental Terms shall have the same
meanings ascribed to them in the Binary Code License
Agreement . These Supplemental Terms shall supersede any
inconsistent or conflicting terms in the Binary Code
License Agreement, or in any license contained within the
Software.

A.Software Internal Use and Development License Grant.
Subject to the terms and conditions of this Agreement,
including, but not limited to the Java Technology
Restrictions of these Supplemental Terms, Sun grants you a
non-exclusive, non-transferable, limited license without
fees to reproduce internally and use internally the
Software complete and unmodified (unless otherwise
specified in the applicable README file) for the purpose of
designing, developing, and testing your Programs.

B.License to Distribute Software. Subject to the terms and
conditions of this Agreement, including, but not limited to
the Java Technology Restrictions of these Supplemental
Terms, Sun grants you a non-exclusive, non-transferable,
limited license without fees to reproduce and distribute
the Software, provided that (i) you distribute the Software
complete and unmodified (unless otherwise specified in the
applicable README file) and only bundled as part of, and
for the sole purpose of running, your Programs, (ii) the
Programs add significant and primary functionality to the
Software, (iii) you do not distribute additional software
intended to replace any component(s) of the Software
(unless otherwise specified in the applicable README file),
(iv) you do not remove or alter any proprietary legends or
notices contained in the Software, (v) you only distribute
the Software subject to a license agreement that protects
Sun's interests consistent with the terms contained in this
Agreement, and (vi) you agree to defend and indemnify Sun
and its licensors from and against any damages, costs,
liabilities, settlement amounts and/or expenses (including
attorneys' fees) incurred in connection with any claim,
lawsuit or action by any third party that arises or results
from the use or distribution of any and all Programs and/or
Software.

C.License to Distribute Redistributables. Subject to the
terms and conditions of this Agreement, including but not
limited to the Java Technology Restrictions of these
Supplemental Terms, Sun grants you a non-exclusive,
non-transferable, limited license without fees to reproduce
and distribute those files specifically identified as
redistributable in the Software "README" file
("Redistributables") provided that: (i) you distribute the
Redistributables complete and unmodified (unless otherwise
specified in the applicable README file), and only bundled
as part of Programs, (ii) you do not distribute additional
software intended to supersede any component(s) of the
Redistributables (unless otherwise specified in the
applicable README file), (iii) you do not remove or alter
any proprietary legends or notices contained in or on the
Redistributables, (iv) you only distribute the
Redistributables pursuant to a license agreement that
protects Sun's interests consistent with the terms
contained in the Agreement, (v) you agree to defend and
indemnify Sun and its licensors from and against any
damages, costs, liabilities, settlement amounts and/or
expenses (including attorneys' fees) incurred in connection
with any claim, lawsuit or action by any third party that
arises or results from the use or distribution of any and
all Programs and/or Software.

D.Java Technology Restrictions. You may not modify the Java
Platform Interface ("JPI", identified as classes contained
within the "java" package or any subpackages of the "java"
package), by creating additional classes within the JPI or
otherwise causing the addition to or modification of the
classes in the JPI.  In the event that you create an
additional class and associated API(s) which (i) extends
the functionality of the Java platform, and (ii) is exposed
to third party software developers for the purpose of
developing additional software which invokes such
additional API, you must promptly publish broadly an
accurate specification for such API for free use by all
developers.  You may not create, or authorize your licensees
to create, additional classes, interfaces, or subpackages
that are in any way identified as "java", "javax", "sun" or
similar convention as specified by Sun in any naming
convention designation.

E.Source Code. Software may contain source code that,
unless expressly licensed for other purposes, is provided
solely for reference purposes pursuant to the terms of this
Agreement. Source code may not be redistributed unless
expressly provided for in this Agreement.

F.Third Party Code. Additional copyright notices and
license terms applicable to portions of the Software are
set forth in the THIRDPARTYLICENSEREADME.txt file. In
addition to any terms and conditions of any third party
opensource/freeware license identified in the
THIRDPARTYLICENSEREADME.txt file, the disclaimer of
warranty and limitation of liability provisions in
paragraphs 5 and 6 of the Binary Code License Agreement
shall apply to all Software in this distribution.

For inquiries please contact: Sun Microsystems, Inc., 4150
Network Circle, Santa Clara, California 95054, U.S.A.
(LFI#141496/Form ID#011801)

=====================================================

Sun Microsystems, Inc. Binary Code
License Agreement
READ THE TERMS OF THIS AGREEMENT AND ANY
PROVIDED SUPPLEMENTAL LICENSE TERMS
(COLLECTIVELY “AGREEMENT”) CAREFULLY
BEFORE OPENING THE SOFTWARE MEDIA PACKAGE.
BY OPENING THE SOFTWARE MEDIA PACKAGE, YOU
AGREE TO THE TERMS OF THIS AGREEMENT. IF YOU
ARE ACCESSING THE SOFTWARE ELECTRONICALLY,
INDICATE YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THESE TERMS BY
SELECTING THE “ACCEPT” BUTTON AT THE END OF
THIS AGREEMENT. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO ALL
THESE TERMS, PROMPTLY RETURN THE UNUSED
SOFTWARE TO YOUR PLACE OF PURCHASE FOR A
REFUND OR, IF THE SOFTWARE IS ACCESSED
ELECTRONICALLY, SELECT THE “DECLINE” BUTTON
AT THE END OF THIS AGREEMENT.

1. LICENSE TO USE.
Sun grants you a non-exclusive and non-transferable
license for the internal use only of the accompanying
software and documentation and any error corrections
provided by Sun (collectively “Software”), by the
number of users and the class of computer hardware
for which the corresponding fee has been paid.

2. RESTRICTIONS.
Software is confidential and copyrighted. Title to
Software and all associated intellectual property rights
is retained by Sun and/or its licensors. Except as
specifically authorized in any Supplemental License
Terms, you may not make copies of Software, other
than a single copy of Software for archival purposes.
Unless enforcement is prohibited by applicable law,
you may not modify, decompile, or reverse engineer
Software. Licensee acknowledges that Licensed
Software is not designed or intended for use in the
design, construction, operation or maintenance of any
nuclear facility. Sun Microsystems, Inc. disclaims any
express or implied warranty of fitness for such uses.
No right, title or interest in or to any trademark,
service mark, logo or trade name of Sun or its licensors
is granted under this Agreement.

3. LIMITED WARRANTY.
Sun warrants to you that for a period of ninety (90)
days from the date of purchase, as evidenced by a copy
of the receipt, the media on which Software is
furnished (if any) will be free of defects in materials
and workmanship under normal use. Except for the
foregoing, Software is provided “AS IS”. Your exclusive
remedy and Sun’s entire liability under this limited
warranty will be at Sun’s option to replace Software
media or refund the fee paid for Software.

4. DISCLAIMER OF WARRANTY.
UNLESS SPECIFIED IN THIS AGREEMENT, ALL
EXPRESS OR IMPLIED CONDITIONS,
REPRESENTATIONS AND WARRANTIES, INCLUDING
ANY IMPLIED WARRANTY OF MERCHANTABILITY,
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE OR NONINFRINGEMENT
ARE DISCLAIMED, EXCEPT TO THE
EXTENT THAT THESE DISCLAIMERS ARE HELD TO
BE LEGALLY INVALID.

5. LIMITATION OF LIABILITY.
LIMITATION OF LIABILITY. TO THE EXTENT NOT
PROHIBITED BY LAW, IN NO EVENT WILL SUN OR
ITS LICENSORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY LOST REVENUE,
PROFIT OR DATA, OR FOR SPECIAL, INDIRECT,
CONSEQUENTIAL, INCIDENTAL OR PUNITIVE
DAMAGES, HOWEVER CAUSED REGARDLESS OF
THE THEORY OF LIABILITY, ARISING OUT OF OR
RELATED TO THE USE OF OR INABILITY TO USE
SOFTWARE, EVEN IF SUN HAS BEEN ADVISED OF
THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES. In no event
will Sun’s liability to you, whether in contract, tort
(including negligence), or otherwise, exceed the
amount paid by you for Software under this
Agreement. The foregoing limitations will apply even
if the above stated warranty fails of its essential
purpose.

6. Termination.
This Agreement is effective until terminated. You may
terminate this Agreement at any time by destroying all
copies of Software. This Agreement will terminate
immediately without notice from Sun if you fail to
comply with any provision of this Agreement. Upon
Termination, you must destroy all copies of Software.

7. Export Regulations.
All Software and technical data delivered under this
Agreement are subject to US export control laws and
may be subject to export or import regulations in other
countries. You agree to comply strictly with all such
laws and regulations and acknowledge that you have
the responsibility to obtain such licenses to export, reexport,
or import as may be required after delivery to
you.

8. U.S. Government Restricted Rights.
If Software is being acquired by or on behalf of the U.S.
Government or by a U.S. Government prime contractor
or subcontractor (at any tier), then the Government’s
rights in Software and accompanying documentation
will be only as set forth in this Agreement; this is in
accordance with 48 CFR 227.7201 through 227.7202-4
(for Department of Defense (DOD) acquisitions) and acquisitions).

9. Governing Law.
Any action related to this Agreement will be governed
by California law and controlling U.S. federal law. No
choice of law rules of any jurisdiction will apply.

10. Severability.
If any provision of this Agreement is held to be
unenforceable, this Agreement will remain in effect
with the provision omitted, unless omission would
frustrate the intent of the parties, in which case this
Agreement will immediately terminate.

11. Integration.
This Agreement is the entire agreement between you
and Sun relating to its subject matter. It supersedes all
prior or contemporaneous oral or written
communications, proposals, representations and
warranties and prevails over any conflicting or
additional terms of any quote, order, acknowledgment,
or other communication between the parties relating
to its subject matter during the term of this
Agreement. No modification of this Agreement will be
binding, unless in writing and signed by an authorized
representative of each party.

=====================================================

Microsoft SQL Server 2000 
Desktop Engine (MSDE). MSDE is redistributed under terms of the MSDN Universal Subscription
as described at http://www.microsoft.com/sql/msde/howtobuy/msderights.mspx.

=====================================================

Xerces 
XML Parser software, which is developed by the Apache Software 
Foundation (http://www.apache.org/). The Xerces software can be obtained
from http://xml.apache.org


the Apache software used in ths product is used under the following license:

/* ========================================================================= *
 *                                                                           *
 *                 The Apache Software License,  Version 1.1                 *
 *                                                                           *
 *         Copyright (c) 1999, 2000  The Apache Software Foundation.         *
 *                           All rights reserved.                            *
 *                                                                           *
 * ========================================================================= *
 *                                                                           *
 * Redistribution and use in source and binary forms,  with or without modi- *
 * fication, are permitted provided that the following conditions are met:   *
 *                                                                           *
 * 1. Redistributions of source code  must retain the above copyright notice *
 *    notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.          *
 *                                                                           *
 * 2. Redistributions  in binary  form  must  reproduce the  above copyright *
 *    notice,  this list of conditions  and the following  disclaimer in the *
 *    documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.   *
 *                                                                           *
 * 3. The end-user documentation  included with the redistribution,  if any, *
 *    must include the following acknowlegement:                             *
 *                                                                           *
 *       "This product includes  software developed  by the Apache  Software *
 *        Foundation <http://www.apache.org/>."                              *
 *                                                                           *
 *    Alternately, this acknowlegement may appear in the software itself, if *
 *    and wherever such third-party acknowlegements normally appear.         *
 *                                                                           *
 * 4. The names  "The  Jakarta  Project",  "Tomcat",  and  "Apache  Software *
 *    Foundation"  must not be used  to endorse or promote  products derived *
 *    from this  software without  prior  written  permission.  For  written *
 *    permission, please contact <apache@apache.org>.                        *
 *                                                                           *
 * 5. Products derived from this software may not be called "Apache" nor may *
 *    "Apache" appear in their names without prior written permission of the *
 *    Apache Software Foundation.                                            *
 *                                                                           *
 * THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS" AND ANY EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES *
 * INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO,  THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY *
 * AND FITNESS FOR  A PARTICULAR PURPOSE  ARE DISCLAIMED.  IN NO EVENT SHALL *
 * THE APACHE  SOFTWARE  FOUNDATION OR  ITS CONTRIBUTORS  BE LIABLE  FOR ANY *
 * DIRECT,  INDIRECT,   INCIDENTAL,  SPECIAL,  EXEMPLARY,  OR  CONSEQUENTIAL *
 * DAMAGES (INCLUDING,  BUT NOT LIMITED TO,  PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS *
 * OR SERVICES;  LOSS OF USE,  DATA,  OR PROFITS;  OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) *
 * HOWEVER CAUSED AND  ON ANY  THEORY  OF  LIABILITY,  WHETHER IN  CONTRACT, *
 * STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT  (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN *
 * ANY  WAY  OUT OF  THE  USE OF  THIS  SOFTWARE,  EVEN  IF  ADVISED  OF THE *
 * POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.                                               *
 *                                                                           *
 * ========================================================================= *
 *                                                                           *
 * This software  consists of voluntary  contributions made  by many indivi- *
 * duals on behalf of the  Apache Software Foundation.  For more information *
 * on the Apache Software Foundation, please see <http://www.apache.org/>.   *
 *                                                                           *
 * ========================================================================= */

=====================================================

PHP5
-------------------------------------------------------------------- 
                  The PHP License, version 3.01
Copyright (c) 1999 - 2006 The PHP Group. All rights reserved.
-------------------------------------------------------------------- 

Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
modification, is permitted provided that the following conditions
are met:

  1. Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.
 
  2. Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright
     notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in
     the documentation and/or other materials provided with the
     distribution.
 
  3. The name "PHP" must not be used to endorse or promote products
     derived from this software without prior written permission. For
     written permission, please contact group@php.net.
  
  4. Products derived from this software may not be called "PHP", nor
     may "PHP" appear in their name, without prior written permission
     from group@php.net.  You may indicate that your software works in
     conjunction with PHP by saying "Foo for PHP" instead of calling
     it "PHP Foo" or "phpfoo"
 
  5. The PHP Group may publish revised and/or new versions of the
     license from time to time. Each version will be given a
     distinguishing version number.
     Once covered code has been published under a particular version
     of the license, you may always continue to use it under the terms
     of that version. You may also choose to use such covered code
     under the terms of any subsequent version of the license
     published by the PHP Group. No one other than the PHP Group has
     the right to modify the terms applicable to covered code created
     under this License.

  6. Redistributions of any form whatsoever must retain the following acknowledgment:
This product includes PHP software, freely available from
<http://www.php.net/software/>.

THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE PHP DEVELOPMENT TEAM ``AS IS'' AND ANY EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO,THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED.  IN NO EVENT SHALL THE PHP DEVELOPMENT TEAM OR ITS CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT,INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT,STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE)
ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.

-------------------------------------------------------------------- 

This software consists of voluntary contributions made by many
individuals on behalf of the PHP Group.

The PHP Group can be contacted via Email at group@php.net.

For more information on the PHP Group and the PHP project, 
please see <http://www.php.net>.

PHP includes the Zend Engine, freely available at
<http://www.zend.com>.

=====================================================

OpenSSL SSL/TLS and cryptographic libraries created and maintained by the OpenSSL Project 
(http://www.openssl.org).


  LICENSE ISSUES
  ==============

  The OpenSSL toolkit stays under a dual license, i.e. both the conditions of
  the OpenSSL License and the original SSLeay license apply to the toolkit.
  See below for the actual license texts. Actually both licenses are BSD-style
  Open Source licenses. In case of any license issues related to OpenSSL
  please contact openssl-core@openssl.org.

  OpenSSL License
  ---------------

/* ====================================================================
 * Copyright (c) 1998-2003 The OpenSSL Project.  All rights reserved.
 *
 * Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
 * modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions
 * are met:
 *
 * 1. Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright
 *    notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.
 *
 * 2. Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright
 *    notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in
 *    the documentation and/or other materials provided with the
 *    distribution.
 *
 * 3. All advertising materials mentioning features or use of this
 *    software must display the following acknowledgment:
 *    "This product includes software developed by the OpenSSL Project
 *    for use in the OpenSSL Toolkit. (http://www.openssl.org/)"
 *
 * 4. The names "OpenSSL Toolkit" and "OpenSSL Project" must not be used to
 *    endorse or promote products derived from this software without
 *    prior written permission. For written permission, please contact
 *    openssl-core@openssl.org.
 *
 * 5. Products derived from this software may not be called "OpenSSL"
 *    nor may "OpenSSL" appear in their names without prior written
 *    permission of the OpenSSL Project.
 *
 * 6. Redistributions of any form whatsoever must retain the following
 *    acknowledgment:
 *    "This product includes software developed by the OpenSSL Project
 *    for use in the OpenSSL Toolkit (http://www.openssl.org/)"
 *
 * THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE OpenSSL PROJECT ``AS IS'' AND ANY
 * EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE
 * IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR
 * PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED.  IN NO EVENT SHALL THE OpenSSL PROJECT OR
 * ITS CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL,
 * SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT
 * NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES;
 * LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION)
 * HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT,
 * STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE)
 * ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED
 * OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.
 * ====================================================================
 *
 * This product includes cryptographic software written by Eric Young
 * (eay@cryptsoft.com).  This product includes software written by Tim
 * Hudson (tjh@cryptsoft.com).
 *
 */

 Original SSLeay License
 -----------------------

/* Copyright (C) 1995-1998 Eric Young (eay@cryptsoft.com)
 * All rights reserved.
 *
 * This package is an SSL implementation written
 * by Eric Young (eay@cryptsoft.com).
 * The implementation was written so as to conform with Netscapes SSL.
 *
 * This library is free for commercial and non-commercial use as long as
 * the following conditions are aheared to.  The following conditions
 * apply to all code found in this distribution, be it the RC4, RSA,
 * lhash, DES, etc., code; not just the SSL code.  The SSL documentation
 * included with this distribution is covered by the same copyright terms
 * except that the holder is Tim Hudson (tjh@cryptsoft.com).
 *
 * Copyright remains Eric Young's, and as such any Copyright notices in
 * the code are not to be removed.
 * If this package is used in a product, Eric Young should be given attribution
 * as the author of the parts of the library used.
 * This can be in the form of a textual message at program startup or
 * in documentation (online or textual) provided with the package.
 *
 * Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
 * modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions
 * are met:
 * 1. Redistributions of source code must retain the copyright
 *    notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.
 * 2. Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright
 *    notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the
 *    documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.
 * 3. All advertising materials mentioning features or use of this software
 *    must display the following acknowledgement:
 *    "This product includes cryptographic software written by
 *     Eric Young (eay@cryptsoft.com)"
 *    The word 'cryptographic' can be left out if the rouines from the library
 *    being used are not cryptographic related :-).
 * 4. If you include any Windows specific code (or a derivative thereof) from
 *    the apps directory (application code) you must include an acknowledgement:
 *    "This product includes software written by Tim Hudson (tjh@cryptsoft.com)"
 *
 * THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY ERIC YOUNG ``AS IS'' AND
 * ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE
 * IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE
 * ARE DISCLAIMED.  IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHOR OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE
 * FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL
 * DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS
 * OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION)
 * HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT
 * LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY
 * OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF
 * SUCH DAMAGE.
 *
 * The licence and distribution terms for any publically available version or
 * derivative of this code cannot be changed.  i.e. this code cannot simply be
 * copied and put under another distribution licence
 * [including the GNU Public Licence.]
 */

=====================================================

zlib library software created and maintained by Jean-loup Gailly and Mark Adler. 
Zlib can be obtained from http://www.gzip.org/zlib/

zlib License
License
/* zlib.h -- interface of the 'zlib' general purpose compression library
  version 1.2.2, October 3rd, 2004

  Copyright (C) 1995-2004 Jean-loup Gailly and Mark Adler

  This software is provided 'as-is', without any express or implied
  warranty.  In no event will the authors be held liable for any damages
  arising from the use of this software.

  Permission is granted to anyone to use this software for any purpose,
  including commercial applications, and to alter it and redistribute it
  freely, subject to the following restrictions:

  1. The origin of this software must not be misrepresented; you must not
     claim that you wrote the original software. If you use this software
     in a product, an acknowledgment in the product documentation would be
     appreciated but is not required.
  2. Altered source versions must be plainly marked as such, and must not be
     misrepresented as being the original software.
  3. This notice may not be removed or altered from any source distribution.

  Jean-loup Gailly jloup@gzip.org
  Mark Adler madler@alumni.caltech.edu

*/

Last modified 22 November 2003
Send all questions about zlib or its license to zlib@gzip.org

      Web page copyright © 1996-2003 Greg Roelofs, Jean-loup Gailly and Mark
      Adler.
      zlib software copyright © 1995-2003 Jean-loup Gailly and Mark Adler.
      Primary site hosted by France Teaser.
      zlib.org domain name donated by Andrew Green.

=====================================================



